<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on hackeryarn</title>
    <link>https://hackeryarn.com/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on hackeryarn</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hackeryarn.com/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s write a macro in Rust - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-2/&#34;&gt;last part&lt;/a&gt; we covered all the fundamental techniques in writing macros. This enables us to write just about any macro we could think of, but knowing a few tricks can make the process much easier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this part, we will build on our &lt;code&gt;where&lt;/code&gt; clause from the previous article. In the process we will allow the &lt;code&gt;where&lt;/code&gt; clause to support multiple comparison operator (instead of just &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt;) as well as multiple ways to join those operators (instead of just &lt;code&gt;and&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s write a macro in Rust - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-1/&#34;&gt;last part&lt;/a&gt; we covered the very basics of macros and implemented a single argument query select. This was a good start, but only scratched the surface of what macros can do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this part we will implement multi-field select and a basic &lt;code&gt;where&lt;/code&gt; clause. That will make our query macro far more useful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;multi-field-select&#34;&gt;Multi-field select&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After being able to select one field, the immediate next thing that comes to mind is selecting multiple fields. Just like before, lets start with the invocation syntax:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s write a macro in Rust - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Macros are required to do some very helpful things in Rust, but this isn&amp;rsquo;t an article about any of those things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I became enamored with macros many years ago when I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://gigamonkeys.com/book/&#34;&gt;Practical Common Lisp&lt;/a&gt; and saw the implementation of a SQL DSL that works with built in data structures. The whole implementation took less than a screen of code and absolutely blew away my expectations of what it took to create DSLs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clojure GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/clojure-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/clojure-actions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently took over the maintenance of an open source Clojure project.&#xA;One of the first things I noticed was the lack CI or CD. These are&#xA;things that aren&amp;rsquo;t required but can save a lot of work, especially for&#xA;a public project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CI portion helps make sure that all pull requests pass tests and&#xA;conform to the project&#39;s coding style. The CD portion helps with&#xA;deploying the project. And these parts become especially important if&#xA;the project is in maintenance mode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Type safe Django app, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/django-returns-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/django-returns-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackeryarn.com/post/django-returns-2/&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; we got a taste of&#xA;using &lt;code&gt;returns&lt;/code&gt; and created our first model methods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this part, we will build out views that interact with databases and learn how to combine returns containers. This composition is the key to effectively using container types and where we will see the benefits of all our work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;writ-views-that-actually-do-something&#34;&gt;Writ views that actually do something&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first view introduced in the official tutorial performs multiple actions which we will split up into individual functions. Writing individual functions will help us give names to the actions that we take, bring the types to the forefront, and clearly demonstrate how to compose small functions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Type safe Django app, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/django-returns-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/django-returns-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackeryarn.com/post/django-returns-1/&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; of this&#xA;series, we looked at how to setup a python project with types, setup our&#xA;project, and used some basic types.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this part we will start working with the database, implement custom&#xA;database methods, and look at how to use &lt;code&gt;returns&lt;/code&gt; to improve the safety&#xA;of those methods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;into-the-database&#34;&gt;Into the database&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s run our initial migrations and get rid of the error that we&#xA;ignored in the first part.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Type safe Django app, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/django-returns-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/django-returns-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Django is a great framework for web development. Unfortunately, due to&#xA;the nature of Python and web development in general, it often leads to&#xA;hard to track down bugs and tangled code. We will take a look at one way&#xA;to reign this in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throughout this series we will follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/4.0/intro/tutorial01/&#34;&gt;official Django&#xA;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; while&#xA;making the code safer and easier to reason about. We will accomplish&#xA;this by enlist the help of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mypy-lang.org/&#34;&gt;mypy&lt;/a&gt; (for general&#xA;type checking) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dry-python/returns&#34;&gt;returns&lt;/a&gt; (for&#xA;containers that will provide safety).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Django with Hy</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/hy-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/hy-django/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hylang.org/en/stable/&#34;&gt;Hy&lt;/a&gt; introduces a List that gives&#xA;you all the power of macros and the elegant Lisp syntax while enabling&#xA;the full power of Python.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although it&#39;s easy enough to use Python libraries in Hy, you just&#xA;import them as you would in Python, I was weary of using a full&#xA;framework outside it&#39;s native language. To prove out this concept, I&#xA;followed &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/3.0/intro/tutorial01/&#34;&gt;the official django&#xA;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; using&#xA;Hy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To my surprise I only ran into minor issues. The rest of the project&#xA;worked flawlessly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLI commands in Emacs</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/cli-in-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/cli-in-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, Gabriel Gonzalez wrote an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.haskellforall.com/2018/10/detailed-walkthrough-for-beginner.html&#34;&gt;excellent&#xA;article&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;on creating useful tools with Haskell. He used an example of a small CLI&#xA;tool that aligns the equals signs of a multi-line text input. The&#xA;article wrapped up by integrating this tool into vim.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love the overarching concept in the article: create small tools that&#xA;are useful in multiple contexts. It&#39;s directly inline with the Unix&#xA;philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only problem is that I am an Emacs user. So in this article, I&#xA;wanted to show how I get the same effect in Emacs. And demonstrating how&#xA;to take CLI interaction in the text editor even further.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchies in Hakyll</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/hierarchies-in-hakyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/hierarchies-in-hakyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating hierarchy in a blog is a useful technique. It allows you to&#xA;have different sections by type of content. It lets users navigate by&#xA;their interests quickly. It makes your blog organized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My need for a hierarchy came when working on another blog - &lt;a href=&#34;https://dailyreadingnotes.com&#34;&gt;Daily&#xA;Reading Notes&lt;/a&gt;. That blog involves notes&#xA;on books I read daily. Since each book has multiple reading notes, I&#xA;wanted to allow two forms of navigation: by a grouping of all notes for&#xA;a particular book and by posted date. The groupings also needed to be&#xA;dynamic. I didn&#39;t want to write code or updated configurations every&#xA;time I added a new book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universally Testable Dependencies in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/universally-testable-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/universally-testable-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JavaScript dependencies are notoriously hard to mock and test across framework&#xA;and environments. However, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dependency_injection%3CPaste%3E&#34;&gt;Dependency Injection&lt;/a&gt; (DI) ensures testability. It&#xA;is common in statically typed languages, like Java or Go, but is also useful in&#xA;dynamic languages like JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article will guide you through a simple technique that can apply&#xA;to any JavaScript code base, frontend or backend, independent of frameworks&#xA;and libraries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The technique I am going to demonstrate is arguably not true DI, since the&#xA;dependencies are still managed by the module using them. However, it&#xA;solves the dependency problem for testing which is the focus of this&#xA;article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ClojureScript Setup for Leiningen Project With Emacs</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/clojurescript-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/clojurescript-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good development environment will boost your productivity in any language. A good Clojure development environment will make you 10x more productive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is focused on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://clojurescript.org/&#34;&gt;ClojureScript&lt;/a&gt; environment for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://leiningen.org/&#34;&gt;Leiningen&lt;/a&gt; based&#xA;project being developed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&#34;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-emacs&#34;&gt;Why Emacs?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Emacs has a great setup for most programming languages but really shines when it&#xA;comes to Lisps, including Clojure. &lt;a href=&#34;https://cider.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;&gt;Cider&lt;/a&gt; is the powerful package that allows easy&#xA;interaction with the Clojure REPL and many IDE like features. In combination with&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/clojure-emacs/clj-refactor.el&#34;&gt;clj-refactor&lt;/a&gt;, you get one of the most powerful toolkits out there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
