<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on hackeryarn</title>
    <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on hackeryarn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hackeryarn.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>It Doesn&#39;t Have to be Crazy at Work - Day 4</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day4/</guid>
      <description>Question the norm and default to no  &amp;ldquo;Culture is what culture does.&amp;rdquo;
 Don&amp;rsquo;t base your culture on best practices. In fact, don&amp;rsquo;t base anything on best practices alone. Only use these practices as a starting point. Strive to push things forward and create something better than the status quo.
To become better than the norm, you need focus. The only way to gain focus is to say no to all the unnecessary things you are saying yes to right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Doesn&#39;t Have to be Crazy at Work - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day3/</guid>
      <description>You work with people  &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s really easy to fall for someone&amp;rsquo;s carefully crafted story.&amp;rdquo;
 &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s really easy to fall for someone&amp;rsquo;s carefully crafted story.&amp;rdquo;
When hiring or just working with someone, get to know them as a person. Everyone has families, hobbies, and worries. Get to know these things, about the people you spend 40 hours a week with. It leads to a better work environment and make sharing ideas easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Doesn&#39;t Have to be Crazy at Work - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day2/</guid>
      <description>Your words carry more power than you think  &amp;ldquo;1 percent occasions like that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t drive policy 99 percent of the time.&amp;rdquo;
 Chances are, you have someone looking up to you or you are an officially a leader. This comes with great responsibility.
Be careful with the example that you set and what you give you attention to. Staying up late, responding to emails on the weekends, and looking at thing &amp;ldquo;just in case&amp;rdquo; all serve to create a bad culture around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Doesn&#39;t Have to be Crazy at Work - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/books/it-doesnt-have-to-be-crazy-at-work/day1/</guid>
      <description>Calm is the Secret to Great Work  &amp;ldquo;Comparison is the death of joy.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ndash; Mark Twain
 Drawn out goals, packed schedules, and crazy work environments sap the calm from any workspace.
Remember that packing your schedule and trying to get more done is not the way to stay creative. Instead allow yourself uninterrupted chunks of time, at least 90 minutes to work. Use this time to to accomplish what you need to and produce something of quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Built a Static Site in Clojure</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/why-i-built-a-static-site-in-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/why-i-built-a-static-site-in-clojure/</guid>
      <description>At a summer barbecue, a friend asked if I could build a website for his new restaurant. But what he didn&#39;t know was that I haven&#39;t built a static site in nearly a decade. However I couldn&#39;t let him spend thousands of dollars on a cookie cutter website designed by a firm that knew nothing about his restaurant.
We started coming up with ideas right away over a couple of beers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Job Isn&#39;t Writing Code</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/your-job-isnt-writing-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/your-job-isnt-writing-code/</guid>
      <description>Every line of code you write is a liability. That line of code you just wrote adds complexity to your code base, gives you more nuances to remember, it might even be a bug. If code is so expensive and dangerous. What can you do? After all, you are a developer.
The answer: You must remember your real job&amp;hellip; Delivering value to the users.
Users don&amp;rsquo;t care what your class hierarchy looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universally Testable Dependencies in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/universally-testable-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/universally-testable-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript dependencies are notoriously hard to mock and test across framework and environments. However, Dependency Injection (DI) ensures testability. It is common in statically typed languages, like Java or Go, but is also useful in dynamic languages like JavaScript.
This article will guide you through a simple technique that can apply to any JavaScript code base, frontend or backend, independent of frameworks and libraries.
The technique I am going to demonstrate is arguably not true DI, since the dependencies are still managed by the module using them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClojureScript Setup for Leiningen Project With Emacs</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/clojurescript-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/clojurescript-setup/</guid>
      <description>A good development environment if fundamental to being productive. This is especially true for Lisps. A good environment can greatly speed up your development process and allow you to utilize the full power of Clojure or any other Lisp.
This tutorial is focused on a ClojureScript environment for a Leiningen based project being developed in Emacs.
Why Emacs? Emacs has a great setup for most programming languages but really shines when it comes to Lisps, including Clojure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Lodash Worked Itself Out of a Job</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/lodash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/lodash/</guid>
      <description>I really loved lodash. It brough the joy of compact functional code to JavaScript. Especially 6 years ago when I first embraced it. It was a wonderful library. Back then, there was no ES6, no Babel, and terrible browser incompatabilities ran rampant. Lodash along with jQuery were the saving light of that time.
I gravitated towards using Lodash because the first language I learned was Scheme. It had functional programing at it&amp;rsquo;s core, and highly influanced how I think about code to this day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient CSV Imports in Rails</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rails-csv-imports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rails-csv-imports/</guid>
      <description>Rails has great capabilities for working CSV files. However, like with many things, the most obvious way is not the most efficient.
We noticed this when our server had major fluctuations in memory consumption. After digging through metrics, made easy thanks to Prometheus and Grafana. We noticed that the spikes were due to our CSV uploads.
Examining CSV Import Our processor is responsible for bringing in coordinates from legacy systems and ones that cannot support our API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix talk</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/phoenix-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/phoenix-talk/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave a talk, at the local Fullstack Meetup, on the Phoenix Framework. Phoenix is the de facto web framework for Elixir.
In this talk, I cover some of the best features of Phoenix:
 Erlang: The platmor which Elixir and Phoenix are build on. (albeit very brief overview of the major features) Plug: The specification for composable module design that gives Phoenix much of it&amp;rsquo;s power. Ecto: The database integration layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy Universal Haskell Development Environment</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/universal-haskell-dev-enviornment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/universal-haskell-dev-enviornment/</guid>
      <description>Haskell is notoriously difficult to setup, which probably led to many people being scared away from ever getting started. However, there has been a lot of work done to address these short comings. And there is a way to setup a very pleasant environment thanks to the hard work of many projects.
Traditional methods included:
 Installing The Haskell Platform, which was a great project in it&amp;rsquo;s time but always seems to lag a few GHC versions behind.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>