<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rust on hackeryarn</title>
    <link>https://hackeryarn.com/tags/rust/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rust on hackeryarn</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hackeryarn.com/tags/rust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s write a macro in Rust - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-2/&#34;&gt;last part&lt;/a&gt; we covered all the fundamental techniques in writing macros. This enables us to write just about any macro we could think of, but knowing a few tricks can make the process much easier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this part, we will build on our &lt;code&gt;where&lt;/code&gt; clause from the previous article. In the process we will allow the &lt;code&gt;where&lt;/code&gt; clause to support multiple comparison operator (instead of just &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt;) as well as multiple ways to join those operators (instead of just &lt;code&gt;and&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s write a macro in Rust - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-1/&#34;&gt;last part&lt;/a&gt; we covered the very basics of macros and implemented a single argument query select. This was a good start, but only scratched the surface of what macros can do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this part we will implement multi-field select and a basic &lt;code&gt;where&lt;/code&gt; clause. That will make our query macro far more useful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;multi-field-select&#34;&gt;Multi-field select&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After being able to select one field, the immediate next thing that comes to mind is selecting multiple fields. Just like before, lets start with the invocation syntax:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s write a macro in Rust - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/rust-macros-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Macros are required to do some very helpful things in Rust, but this isn&amp;rsquo;t an article about any of those things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I became enamored with macros many years ago when I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://gigamonkeys.com/book/&#34;&gt;Practical Common Lisp&lt;/a&gt; and saw the implementation of a SQL DSL that works with built in data structures. The whole implementation took less than a screen of code and absolutely blew away my expectations of what it took to create DSLs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
