<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clojure on hackeryarn</title>
    <link>https://hackeryarn.com/categories/clojure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clojure on hackeryarn</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hackeryarn.com/categories/clojure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clojure GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/clojure-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/clojure-actions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;I recently took over the maintenance of an open source Clojure project. One of the first things I noticed was the lack CI or CD. These are things that aren&amp;#39;t required but can save a lot of work, especially for a public project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;The CI portion helps make sure that all pull requests pass tests and conform to the project&amp;#39;s coding style. The CD portion helps with deploying the project. And these parts become especially important if the project is in maintenance mode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Built a Static Site in Clojure</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/why-i-built-a-static-site-in-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/why-i-built-a-static-site-in-clojure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;At a summer barbecue, a friend asked if I could build a website for his new&#xA;restaurant. But what he didn&amp;#39;t know was that I haven&amp;#39;t built a static site in nearly a&#xA;decade. However I couldn&amp;#39;t let him spend thousands of dollars on a cookie cutter&#xA;website designed by a firm that knew nothing about his restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;We started coming up with ideas right away over a couple of beers.&#xA;He wanted manageable content, an Instagram feed, and an easy to change restaurant&#xA;menu. It quickly started sounding like a full on Content Management System and&#xA;not a simple website. I had to reel in this ambitious project before it&#xA;became a feature sink. So we decided to just make a beautiful static site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
