<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Discussion on hackeryarn</title>
    <link>https://hackeryarn.com/tags/discussion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Discussion on hackeryarn</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hackeryarn.com/tags/discussion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You don&#39;t need a map for that</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/maps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most misused data structures is the humble map; hashmap,&#xA;dictionary, hash table, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a great data structure for quick storage and access of key value&#xA;pairs. Unfortunately, because of its ease and availability, it becomes&#xA;pervasive at jobs it has no business doing. The problem grows most&#xA;visible in dynamically typed languages that make the map a first class&#xA;citizen (Python, Ruby, Clojure, etc.), but it can creep up in any&#xA;language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When DRY goes wrong</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/dry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/dry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DRY has become a mantra throughout the industry. Any time repetitive code shows up, DRY gets applied as a cure all. If you even start to question DRYing up a piece of code, you are viewed as a heretic to the entire industry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ok, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not that bad, but many times DRY gets applied without much thought. This careless application of DRY leads to brittle code, making even simple changes scary because they could have a huge ripple effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Picking a Linux Distro</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/picking-a-linux-distro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/picking-a-linux-distro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started a new job that gave me the chance to run whatever Linux distribution would make me the most productive. In the face of complete freedom, I decided to re-evaluate my daily driver and see if there was a distribution that would give me the most up-to-date software while maintaining a stable system. The results of my search surprised even me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have ran Ubuntu on my home lab server for over a decade, and used it a daily driver from 2009 to 2014. I switched from Ubuntu because their package release cycle, even on the latest version, is too slow for my liking. At around the same time, rolling release distros were gaining popularity. So I jumped on the Arch train.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embrace your constraints</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/embrace-the-constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/embrace-the-constraints/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Engineers want to measure the quality and effectiveness of their work.&#xA;They turn to code coverage, burn down charts, and yearly goals, with the&#xA;best intention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These measurements provide quantitative data about how much planned work&#xA;was delivered, but they fail to tie the work to outcome. What good are&#xA;1,000 lines of code if the users never use the feature? These metrics&#xA;distract from the two question every professional should ask:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Right Abstraction for Lambdas</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/the-right-abstraction-for-lambdas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/the-right-abstraction-for-lambdas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Serverless functions are a great alternative for many light tasks that would&#xA;traditionally required a server. They allow you to split up work across&#xA;mutiple small functions, and you only pay&#xA;for what you use. On top of that, they require less maintenance than managing your own&#xA;server or Kubernetes cluster.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the single function per lambda approach can become too granular. Shared&#xA;functionality becomes hard to group together. You only have hard to enforce naming convention&#xA;for lambda that belong together. Then comes the problem of sharing code between lamdas. Do you need a library for a few common functions?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Built a Static Site in Clojure</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/why-i-built-a-static-site-in-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/why-i-built-a-static-site-in-clojure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At a summer barbecue, a friend asked if I could build a website for his&#xA;new restaurant. But what he didn&#39;t know was that I haven&#39;t built a&#xA;static site in nearly a decade. However I couldn&#39;t let him spend&#xA;thousands of dollars on a cookie cutter website designed by a firm that&#xA;knew nothing about his restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We started coming up with ideas right away over a couple of beers. He&#xA;wanted manageable content, an Instagram feed, and an easy to change&#xA;restaurant menu. It quickly started sounding like a full on Content&#xA;Management System and not a simple website. I had to reel in this&#xA;ambitious project before it became a feature sink. So we decided to just&#xA;make a beautiful static site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Job Isn&#39;t Writing Code</title>
      <link>https://hackeryarn.com/post/your-job-isnt-writing-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hackeryarn.com/post/your-job-isnt-writing-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every line of code you write is a liability. That line of code you just wrote&#xA;adds complexity to your code base, gives you more nuances to remember, it&#xA;might even be a bug. If code is so expensive and dangerous. What can you do?&#xA;After all, you are a developer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The answer: You must remember your real job&amp;hellip; Delivering value to the users.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Users don&amp;rsquo;t care what your class hierarchy looks like. They don&amp;rsquo;t care which&#xA;language or framework you&amp;rsquo;re using. They don&amp;rsquo;t even care if your system is a&#xA;cloud ready microservice. The user only cares that your product is helping them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
